

MUHAMMAD RIFKI ADAM A

+6285641737076 | mrifkiadama@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrifkiadama/ | https://github.com/mrifkiadama

Salam, Magelang, Central Java, Indonesia

Hello! My name is Muhammad Rifki Adam A. I am a website developer based in Yogyakarta Indonesia. My interest and focus is website development. I am a person who is very enthusiastic about things related to technology, enjoys learning and exploring new things in the technology that I use and even technology that is beyond my reach. I have worked as a Website Developer for over 4 years and freelanced for the last 1 year.

Work Experiences

PT BALEO MOL INDONESIA - Semarang, Indonesia

Dec 2021 - Present

Fullstack Developer / Full-time

- Activate SSL(Secure Socket Layer) and domain
- · Fixed feature bugs that were already running
- · Implementation of the Repository Pattern and Refactor code
- Make improvements to database queries and the appearance of the website that is already running
- Migrate images on local storage into Amazon S3
- Create and integrate the admin panel API into the landingpage builder application feature

PT BALEO MOL INDONESIA - Semarang, Indonesia

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

Web Developer / Full-time

Baleomol is a marketplace that brings together people who already have products (Supplier) and people who don't have products (Dropshippers) to be resold to other platforms even without having to stock products.

- · Communicating with the team and designing the Sprint Planning
- Develop and maintain web applications using the PHP (Laravel), Jquery, Bootstrap 4, and Plugin GrapesJs
- · Designing databases
- Manually operating and testing applications
- · Create a landingpage view template
- · Create and develop existing features on the admin panel
- · Create, design, build and develop landingpage builder websites

Koperasi Property Today Indonesia - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Apr 2019 - May 2020

Frontend Developer / Full-time

Koperasi Property Today Indonesia (KPTI) is a service agency engaged in the field of property, construction and property consulting.

- Create, design and develop a company profile website
- Implementation of UI/UX design in the appearance of website program code
- Develop and maintain web applications using the PHP (Codeigniter).
- Working as digital marketing helps market products through Facebook ads and creates interactive landing page websites for product sales advertisements

PT Olsera Indonesia Pratama - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Mar 2019 - May 2019

Mobile Developer / Internship

Olsera is a one-stop solution for POS and Online Stores. With Olsera, MSME players can easily manage sales at physical stores and online stores simultaneously with synchronized solutions for product data, inventory, sales and reports.

Olsera POS can be used on Android, iOS and Windows.

- Participated in developing cashier app about spa treatments
- Implementation of UI/UX design into the program code view
- · Implementation of login and register features using social media accounts such as gmail, Facebook on react native technology

UIN Sunan Kalijaga Yogyakarta - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

Assistant Lecturer

Assisting lecturers in course practicum operating system

Education Level

Universitas Islam Negeri Sunan Kalijaga Yogyakarta - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Sep 2016 - Aug 2020

Bachelor Degree in Informatics Engineering

SMA N 1 NGLUWAR - Magelang, Indonesia

May 2013 - May 2016

Senior High School in Sains

Dicoding Indonesia @ - Indonesia

Certificate in Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Web dengan React

Dicoding Indonesia **⊘** - Indonesia

Certificate in Belajar Membuat Front-End Web untuk Pemula

Dicoding Indonesia **⊙** - Indonesia

Certificate in Architecting on AWS (Membangun Arsitektur Cloud di AWS)

Dicoding Indonesia **⊙** - Indonesia

Certificate in Belajar Dasar Pemrograman JavaScript

Dicoding Indonesia **⊙** - Indonesia

Certificate in Cloud Practitioner Essentials (Belajar Dasar AWS Cloud)

Dicoding Indonesia @ - Indonesia

Certificate in Belajar Fundamental Front-End Web Development

Trainocate Indonesia @ - Indonesia

Certificate in AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials

BuildWithAngga @ - Indonesia

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Developer: Toko Online

Progate @ - Indonesia

Certificate in Web Development Path (Node.js)

Dicoding Indonesia @ - Indonesia

Certificate in Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Android untuk Pemula

Organization Experience

HMPS (Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Informatika) - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Feb 2018 - Feb 2019

Sponsorship Division

- Make a list of which parties will be invited to cooperate
- Think about and plan other sources of funding that provide income
- Find the intended sponsor's contact.
- · Create sponsorship proposals
- · Organize and make sponsorship proposals.

Idept (Informatic Departement) - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Apr 2018 - Jun 2019

Member

It is an organization / study club formed to accommodate student learning needs that focus on multimedia sciences such as graphic design, web design, and photo and video editing.

Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

• **Skills**: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, PHP, Codeigniter, Laravel, Javascript, GrapesJs, Jquery, Node Js, React Js, Java, React Native, AWS S3, AWS Route 53, Amazon SQS, Application versioning (Git), styled-components, JSON data format, RESTful API